<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Emmy Steven</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Emmy Steven</description>
    <image>
      <title>Emmy Steven</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/img/feature-image.webp</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/img/feature-image.webp</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 09:07:47 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Get an EIN for Free</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/get-free-ein/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 09:07:47 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/get-free-ein/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to get an EIN for free: a step-by-step guide to applying online with the IRS. Perfect for new business owners and freelancers!</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<p>Forming an LLC in the U.S. can be exciting, but then you realize that you can open a business bank account especially if you are a non-US citizen or resident.</p>
<p>If you can not open a business account for your newly formed LLC, then you can&rsquo;t receive payment, and one major requirement to open a business bank account is the EIN - Employer Identification Number.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, there is so much false information online regarding non-US citizens and non-US residents (foreigners) obtaining an Employer Identification Number (EIN) from the IRS.</p>
<p>A majority of the information is inaccurate or insufficient, either as a result of limited understanding or an attempt to push a sale on you.</p>
<p>Here are the things you should keep in mind as we proceed:</p>
<ul>
<li>You don&rsquo;t need to pay to get an EIN</li>
<li>You don&rsquo;t need to be a U.S citizen or U.S resident to get an EIN</li>
<li>You don&rsquo;t need an SSN to get an EIN</li>
<li>You don&rsquo;t need an ITIN to get an EIN</li>
<li>You don&rsquo;t need a Third Party Designee to get an EIN</li>
<li>You don&rsquo;t need a lawyer or accountant to get an EIN</li>
<li>You don&rsquo;t need a U.S. address to get an EIN</li>
</ul>
<p>Whether you are a U.S. citizen or not, this blog post will guide you on how to get an EIN seamlessly without having to pay a dime to any agent.</p>
<br/>
<h3 id="what-is-an-ein">What is an EIN?</h3>
<p>An Employer Identification Number aids the IRS in identifying your business for tax purposes. Small lenders and financial institutions will require this number before granting access to financial products for your small business. Each EIN consists of nine digits, and no two businesses can be allocated identical EINs. The format includes a hyphen between the second and third digits, creating XX-XXXXXXX.</p>
<br/>
<h3 id="why-you-need-an-ein">Why You Need an EIN</h3>
<p>Starting a partnership requires obtaining an EIN, which is mandated by the IRS for specific fields. To employ workers and acquire business permits, business owners must possess this tax identification number. Nevertheless, it&rsquo;s not required to have an EIN to collaborate with freelancers. If you have a Keogh retirement plan or withhold taxes on non-wage income, you will also require an EIN.</p>
<p>Business owners who have EINs can establish business bank accounts to distinguish personal finances from business finances. Keeping personal and business tax returns separate can simplify tax filing and help accurately determine the amount of income tax owed.</p>
<p>Your EIN will be used for U.S. tax reporting and filing obligations, as well as for hiring employees (if necessary) and obtaining sales tax licenses/permits.</p>
<p>The EIN of your LLC will be used to sign up for accounts on platforms such as eBay, Amazon FBA, Youtube, Google Adsense, Shopify, Paypal, Stripe, and others.</p>
<p>An EIN also offers increased privacy by allowing you to utilize it for crucial business paperwork instead of your Social Security Number. Having additional privacy can lower the chances of becoming a victim of identity theft.</p>
<br/>
<h3 id="how-long-does-it-take-to-get-an-ein">How Long Does it Take to Get an EIN?</h3>
<p>The amount of time it takes to receive an EIN varies depending on the method of application used. If you submit your application online, you&rsquo;ll get a quick response.</p>
<p>If you send your application via fax may extend the processing time from two weeks to four weeks</p>
<p>If you send your application through the mail (not email) it may extend the processing time to six months. Send your EIN application by mail, may take as long as four weeks to eight weeks for you to hear back from the IRS.</p>
<br/>
<h3 id="how-to-apply-for-an-ein-online">How to Apply for an EIN Online</h3>
<p>The process of applying online for a free EIN is simple. To apply for an EIN, you must have any of the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>a legitimate Social Security Number (SSN),</li>
<li>a valid Taxpayer Identification Number (TIN), or</li>
<li>an active EIN</li>
</ul>
<p>If you have any of these, you can begin by following these steps.</p>
<br/>
<p><strong>Step 1: Visit The IRS Website</strong><br>
The application process for the IRS is simple and easy to follow. You must go to the <a
    
        href="https://www.irs.gov/businesses/small-businesses-self-employed/apply-for-an-employer-identification-number-ein-online" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" style="color: #eb5757;"

    

    >
    
    <span style="color: #eb5757;"> IRS website </span>

    
        <span style="white-space: nowrap;">&thinsp;<svg
            style="height: 0.7em; width: 0.7em;" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="external-link-alt"
            class="svg-inline--fa fa-external-link-alt fa-w-16" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
            viewBox="0 0 512 512">
            <title>external link</title>
            <path fill="currentColor"
                d="M432,320H400a16,16,0,0,0-16,16V448H64V128H208a16,16,0,0,0,16-16V80a16,16,0,0,0-16-16H48A48,48,0,0,0,0,112V464a48,48,0,0,0,48,48H400a48,48,0,0,0,48-48V336A16,16,0,0,0,432,320ZM488,0h-128c-21.37,0-32.05,25.91-17,41l35.73,35.73L135,320.37a24,24,0,0,0,0,34L157.67,377a24,24,0,0,0,34,0L435.28,133.32,471,169c15,15,41,4.5,41-17V24A24,24,0,0,0,488,0Z">
            </path>
        </svg></span>
    
</a>
 to begin the process.</p>
<br/>
<p><strong>Step 2: Fill in the form</strong><br>
The IRS will inquire about the purpose of your EIN request and who is responsible for the company&rsquo;s tax matters.</p>
<p>You will need to provide essential details such as your:</p>
<ul>
<li>Full name,</li>
<li>Type of business entity,</li>
<li>Business location, and</li>
<li>Contact number.</li>
</ul>
<p>You have the option to get a confirmation letter either online or through regular mail.</p>
<p>Getting confirmation through postal mail may take a couple of weeks, whereas online delivery provides instant access to your confirmation.</p>
<p>You must finish the entire application in one go as the session will end after 15 minutes of inactivity. If that occurs, you will need to begin the application process from the beginning.</p>
<br/>
<p><strong>Step 3: Review your EIN application</strong><br>
It will only take you a minute or two to cross-check your EIN application and make sure there are no errors. Going over your application can prevent additional complications down the line.</p>
<br/>
<p><strong>Step 4: Submit your application</strong><br>
Once you are super confident with your EIN application, it’s time to submit it. If you apply online, you can instantly receive your EIN.</p>
<br/>
<h3 id="how-to-apply-for-an-ein-via-fax">How to Apply for an EIN via Fax</h3>
<br/>
<h3 id="what-happens-if-you-lose-your-ein">What happens if you lose your EIN?</h3>
<p>If you lose your EIN, you should first search for the online letter you received from the IRS upon getting approved. You can also look through your filed tax returns, which list your EIN, or contact the bank that provides your business accounts. You can also call the IRS Business &amp; Specialty Tax Line during business hours if you can&rsquo;t find your EIN.</p>
<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<br/>



<a class="hugo-shortcodes-bmc-button" href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/techwritas" target="_blank">
    <img src="https://img.buymeacoffee.com/button-api/?button_colour=ffdd00&amp;coffee_colour=ffffff&amp;emoji=&amp;font_colour=000000&amp;font_family=Cookie&amp;outline_colour=000000&amp;slug=techwritas&amp;text=Buy&#43;us&#43;a&#43;coffee" alt="Buy us a coffee" />
</a>
<br/>
<h3 id="frequently-asked-questions">Frequently Asked Questions</h3>
<p><strong>What does the EIN reference number 101 mean?</strong><br>
An EIN Error 101 occurs when the IRS identifies a different entity with the same business name. If you receive an Error 101 after submitting your EIN, you will need to submit a new application for your EIN using form SS-4.</p>
<p><strong>Can I get an EIN if I&rsquo;m not a US citizen?</strong><br>
A common misconception is that an individual needs a Social Security number (SSN) to obtain a business EIN, but this is not true. Foreigners who own businesses can obtain a business EIN even without having an SSN.</p>
<p><strong>Is US tax ID the same as EIN?</strong><br>
A Federal Tax Identification Number also referred to as a &ldquo;95 Number&rdquo;, &ldquo;E.I.N. Number,&rdquo; or &ldquo;Tax I.D. Number&rdquo;, is a nine-digit number issued by the IRS. Different titles refer to identical numerical value.</p>
<br/>
<iframe
    src="https://techwritas.substack.com/embed"
    style="width:100%; height:150px; border:none; overflow:hidden; border-radius:15px;">
</iframe>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Medium vs Substack</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/medium-vs-substack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 16:08:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/medium-vs-substack/</guid>
      <description>Uncover which platform suits you best: Medium or Substack? Learn about their unique benefits, monetization options, and impact on your writing career.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<p>As a writer eager to publish articles and thought pieces, you might be considering platforms like Medium and Substack. These two popular sites offer distinct pathways for content creators, each with its unique advantages.</p>
<p>Medium is often seen as more beginner-friendly, offering a built-in audience and an easy start for new writers.</p>
<p>On the other hand, Substack provides a straightforward, free setup with the potential for subscription-based income, making it an attractive option for those looking to monetize their audience.</p>
<p>Let’s dive deeper into the differences and find out which platform suits your writing journey best.</p>
<br>
<h2 id="substack-vs-medium-at-a-glance">Substack vs. Medium at a Glance</h2>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Feature</th>
          <th>Medium</th>
          <th>Substack</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td><strong>Founded</strong></td>
          <td>2012</td>
          <td>2017</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td><strong>Target</strong></td>
          <td>Independent authors and writers</td>
          <td>Columnists, Journalists, political commentators</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td><strong>Revenue</strong></td>
          <td>Offers readers a $5 monthly membership.</td>
          <td>Charges a 10% fee on subscriptions charged by writers to their audience.</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td><strong>Monetization</strong></td>
          <td>Earnings generated from the Medium Partner Program.</td>
          <td>Offering a subscription-based newsletter to your readers.</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<br>
<h3 id="medium">Medium</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/img/01-medium-vs-substack.webp" alt="Medium | techwritas.com"  />
<br>
<a
    
        href="https://medium.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" style="color: #eb5757;"

    

    >
    
    <span style="color: #eb5757;"> Medium </span>

    
        <span style="white-space: nowrap;">&thinsp;<svg
            style="height: 0.7em; width: 0.7em;" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="external-link-alt"
            class="svg-inline--fa fa-external-link-alt fa-w-16" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
            viewBox="0 0 512 512">
            <title>external link</title>
            <path fill="currentColor"
                d="M432,320H400a16,16,0,0,0-16,16V448H64V128H208a16,16,0,0,0,16-16V80a16,16,0,0,0-16-16H48A48,48,0,0,0,0,112V464a48,48,0,0,0,48,48H400a48,48,0,0,0,48-48V336A16,16,0,0,0,432,320ZM488,0h-128c-21.37,0-32.05,25.91-17,41l35.73,35.73L135,320.37a24,24,0,0,0,0,34L157.67,377a24,24,0,0,0,34,0L435.28,133.32,471,169c15,15,41,4.5,41-17V24A24,24,0,0,0,488,0Z">
            </path>
        </svg></span>
    
</a>
 is a platform that allows anyone to share their essays without requiring a personal website, and it is open-source.</p>
<p>Medium provides aspiring writers with an established readership, which can assist in growing your audience without the gradual process often associated with SEO.</p>
<br>
<h3 id="substack">Substack</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/img/02-medium-vs-substack.webp" alt="Substack | techwritas.com"  />
<br>
<a
    
        href="https://substack.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" style="color: #eb5757;"

    

    >
    
    <span style="color: #eb5757;"> Substack </span>

    
        <span style="white-space: nowrap;">&thinsp;<svg
            style="height: 0.7em; width: 0.7em;" focusable="false" data-prefix="fas" data-icon="external-link-alt"
            class="svg-inline--fa fa-external-link-alt fa-w-16" role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
            viewBox="0 0 512 512">
            <title>external link</title>
            <path fill="currentColor"
                d="M432,320H400a16,16,0,0,0-16,16V448H64V128H208a16,16,0,0,0,16-16V80a16,16,0,0,0-16-16H48A48,48,0,0,0,0,112V464a48,48,0,0,0,48,48H400a48,48,0,0,0,48-48V336A16,16,0,0,0,432,320ZM488,0h-128c-21.37,0-32.05,25.91-17,41l35.73,35.73L135,320.37a24,24,0,0,0,0,34L157.67,377a24,24,0,0,0,34,0L435.28,133.32,471,169c15,15,41,4.5,41-17V24A24,24,0,0,0,488,0Z">
            </path>
        </svg></span>
    
</a>
 is a digital platform that allows individuals to begin and grow a newsletter. Many writers are drawn to its features for paid newsletters, added social features, and coolness.</p>
<p>If your Substack newsletter doesn&rsquo;t have engaging content that readers want to share, you&rsquo;ll have to create a digital marketing plan to promote it when you begin writing.</p>
<br/>
<h3 id="similarities-between-medium-and-substack">Similarities between Medium and Substack</h3>
<ul>
<li>Offer content for free or monetize it with exclusive member-only access.</li>
<li>Both platforms promote your writing to their audiences, with Medium’s algorithm favoring new writers.</li>
<li>Access detailed audience analytics on both.</li>
<li>Readers can comment and share opinions on articles.</li>
</ul>
<br/>
<h3 id="differences-between-medium-and-substack">Differences between Medium and Substack</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Monetization</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Medium</strong>:<br>
Monetization is based on the number of people who become premium members via your referral link and the time premium members spend reading your articles.</li>
<li><strong>Substack</strong>:<br>
You earn revenue through paid subscriptions on a monthly or yearly basis, providing a more consistent income flow compared to Medium.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Requirements for Monetization</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Medium</strong>:<br>
In order to be monetized you need a minimum of one published article, a minimum of 100 followers, and have posted at least once within the last 6 months.</li>
<li><strong>Substack</strong>:<br>
No requirements for you to get monetized (however, they take 10% of your subscription revenue)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Features</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Medium</strong>:<br>
You have the option to create or join publications. These are shared spaces for stories focused around a common theme, usually written by multiple writers.</li>
<li><strong>Substack</strong>:<br>
You have control over your email list, giving you the ability to view and export individual emails, a feature that Medium lacks.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Audience Reach</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Medium</strong>:<br>
Medium can be taken as a social media platform for writers. You may want to focus your attention there if you don&rsquo;t have an established following yet.</li>
<li><strong>Substack</strong>:<br>
Substack doesn&rsquo;t provide an avenue for you to grow your audience, as only your subscribers can view your content due to its focus on email newsletters.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Content Focus</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Medium</strong>:<br>
Emphasis is placed on producing a high volume of content that can quickly gain popularity. The platform’s algorithm often favors articles that can reach a broad audience through shares and engagement, rewarding writers who can capture immediate attention.</li>
<li><strong>Substack</strong>:<br>
Emphasis is placed on building a dedicated reader base through high-quality, thoughtful content. It prioritizes developing a loyal audience willing to subscribe and support the writer consistently.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Platform Purpose</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Medium</strong>:<br>
It acts as a launchpad for writers seeking exposure. It’s ideal for reaching a large audience quickly and is useful for testing ideas and gaining initial traction in the writing community.</li>
<li><strong>Substack</strong>:<br>
Serves as a destination for writers looking to monetize their work directly. It’s great for building a sustainable writing career by developing a subscription-based revenue model.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Engagement</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Medium</strong>:<br>
Encourages experimentation by allowing writers to publish a variety of content types and styles. The platform supports diverse topics and writing forms, making it a good place for writers to explore different ideas.</li>
<li><strong>Substack</strong>:<br>
Demands commitment from writers who aim to build and maintain a subscriber base. Consistent publishing and engagement are crucial for retaining subscribers and growing readership.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Goals</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Exposure</strong>:<br>
Medium is the better choice for writers looking to gain visibility and reach a wide audience quickly.</li>
<li><strong>Income</strong>:<br>
Substack is more suited for writers who want to generate income through subscriptions and are willing to invest in building a loyal readership.</li>
<li><strong>Community and Impact</strong>:<br>
Substack fosters community through direct communication with subscribers, while either platform can have an impact, depending on how it aligns with your objectives.<br>
Medium can also build community through its network of writers and readers, though Substack provides a more personal connection.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Medium and Substack both have their pros and cons that the other does not possess. To maximize productivity, it is important to customize your writing approach according to these strengths and limitations.</p>
<p>I will stress that the most effective way to decide is by experimenting with these platforms personally. While I have attempted to provide helpful information in this article, I have not taken into account your personal experience, viewpoint, and objectives. No other author who writes about this topic can do so.</p>
<br/>



<a class="hugo-shortcodes-bmc-button" href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/techwritas" target="_blank">
    <img src="https://img.buymeacoffee.com/button-api/?button_colour=ffdd00&amp;coffee_colour=ffffff&amp;emoji=&amp;font_colour=000000&amp;font_family=Cookie&amp;outline_colour=000000&amp;slug=techwritas&amp;text=Buy&#43;us&#43;a&#43;coffee" alt="Buy us a coffee" />
</a>
<br/>
<h3 id="frequently-asked-questions">Frequently Asked Questions</h3>
<p><strong>Are Medium and Substack the same?</strong><br>
Substack enables freelance writers to utilize paid subscription features. Nevertheless, Medium offers a wider audience, improved visibility, and instant earning potential.<br>
<br/></p>
<p><strong>What is the downside of Substack?</strong><br>
Substack can become costly. If you choose to make money from your Substack, 10% will be deducted by them and an extra 3% will be taken by Stripe, totaling 13% of your earnings automatically deducted. This could cost more than the typical monthly newsletter subscription services.<br>
<br/></p>
<p><strong>What is Medium best used for?</strong><br>
Medium is a platform where individuals have access to significant, thought-provoking stories about their interests and can also exchange ideas with a global audience.</p>
<br/>
<iframe
    src="https://techwritas.substack.com/embed"
    style="width:100%; height:150px; border:none; overflow:hidden; border-radius:15px;">
</iframe>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Form a US LLC</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/form-us-llc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 08:58:27 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/form-us-llc/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to form a US LLC with this comprehensive guide. From choosing a name to filing paperwork, get all the steps and tips you need for a successful setup</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<br/>



<a class="hugo-shortcodes-bmc-button" href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/techwritas" target="_blank">
    <img src="https://img.buymeacoffee.com/button-api/?button_colour=ffdd00&amp;coffee_colour=ffffff&amp;emoji=&amp;font_colour=000000&amp;font_family=Cookie&amp;outline_colour=000000&amp;slug=techwritas&amp;text=Buy&#43;us&#43;a&#43;coffee" alt="Buy us a coffee" />
</a>
<br/>
<h3 id="frequently-asked-questions">Frequently Asked Questions</h3>
<br/>
<iframe
    src="https://techwritas.substack.com/embed"
    style="width:100%; height:150px; border:none; overflow:hidden; border-radius:15px;">
</iframe>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Avoid Rug Pulls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/how-to-avoid-rug-pulls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 10:39:28 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/how-to-avoid-rug-pulls/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to get an EIN for free: a step-by-step guide to applying online with the IRS. Perfect for new business owners and freelancers!</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="red-flags">Red Flags</h3>
<p><strong>Unrealistic Promises</strong></p>
<p>are they responsive or evasive</p>
<h3 id="stay-updated-with-market-trends">Stay Updated with Market Trends</h3>
<p>Follow their 𝕏 handle<br>
Check if they have liquidity<br>
Check if the project has utility especially if it is DeFi project<br>
Enable 2fa on your wallets</p>
<p>use a secure wallet, preferably cold storage</p>
<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<br/>



<a class="hugo-shortcodes-bmc-button" href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/techwritas" target="_blank">
    <img src="https://img.buymeacoffee.com/button-api/?button_colour=ffdd00&amp;coffee_colour=ffffff&amp;emoji=&amp;font_colour=000000&amp;font_family=Cookie&amp;outline_colour=000000&amp;slug=techwritas&amp;text=Buy&#43;us&#43;a&#43;coffee" alt="Buy us a coffee" />
</a>
<br/>
<h3 id="frequently-asked-questions">Frequently Asked Questions</h3>
<br/>
<iframe
    src="https://techwritas.substack.com/embed"
    style="width:100%; height:150px; border:none; overflow:hidden; border-radius:15px;">
</iframe>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
